Guide to the Stanford University, Program in Comparative Studies in Race and Ethnicity, Honors Theses
Stanford University Libraries.
Dept. of Special Collections & University Archives.
Stanford University, Program in Comparative Studies in Race and Ethnicity, honors theses
1989-2014
SC4-6531
Stanford University. Program in Comparative Studies in Race and Ethnicity
1.25 Linear feet (17 volumes in 3 boxes)
Honors theses written by undergraduate students in the Stanford University Program in Comparative Studies in Race and Ethnicity.
Dept. of Special Collections & University Archives. Stanford University Libraries. 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: speccollref@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Provenance
Materials were transferred to the Stanford University Archives by the Program in Comparative Studies in Race and Ethnicity in 2006. Additional theses were transferred to the Stanford University Archives from the Hume Writing Center in 2011.
Information about Access
The collection is open for research; materials must be requested at least 48 hours in advance of intended use. No photocopies may be made.
Scope and Contents note
The collection consists of honors theses written by undergraduate students in the Stanford University Program in Comparative Studies in Race and Ethnicity.
Access Terms
Stanford University. Program in Comparative Studies in Race and Ethnicity; Cultural pluralism; Multiculturalism
Collection Contents
- Theses, 2006; Accession ARCH-2006-097
  - Vaughan, Christopher R., The history of labor at Stanford, 1969-2003., 2006 May
- Theses, Accession ARCH-2011-152
  - Anyon, Yolanda, Recipients' perspectivies on the implementation of welfare reform: Oakland as a case study., undated (Box 1)
  - Dillard, Mary, The Afro-American community in Kwame Nkrumah's Ghana: 1951 to 1966., 1990 (Box 1)
  - Greatorex-Voith, Siobhan, Class and inequality in higher education: the experiences of low-income students in elite higher education contexts., 2008 (Box 1)
  - Kehrer, Stephanie, The identity dilemma: education, identity and the legacy of guest worker programs: the case of Turkish-German and Mexican-American youth., 2001 (Box 1)
  - Kim, Bryan, The AZN youth subculture: divergent conceptions of panethnicity in the emerging Asian American second generation., 2004 (Box 1)
  - Muñiz Arnal, Dayna B., La Jaula de Oro: negotiating an "Illegal Alien" identity in the militarized American state., 2003? (Box 1)
  - Stebing, Holly Miowak, Rewriting the history of racial segregation in Alaska., 2009 (Box 1)
  - Sykes, Sunshine, Becoming through writing: a reclamation of voice and memory in American Indian women's poetry., 1997 (Box 1)
  - Lu, Elaine, Antithetical self-identification and yellow peril: Chinese and Japanese stereotypes in American comic art, 1869-1949., 1989 (Box 1)
  - Park, Jieun Grace, Language and ethnicity: the identity of third generation Korean residents in Japan., 2000 (Box 1)
  - Salzman, Amanda, Revolution through education: an analysis of Neve Shalom/Wahat al-Salam and the ramifications of integrated schools in Israel., 2000 (Box 1)
  - Rico, Gabriela, Guare, Nandi, Nana Ke'ri, Jingonikua, Ireri (woman, mother, grandmother, sister, queen): motherhood, empowerment and resistance: Purepecha women in two indigenous communities in Michoacan, Mexico., 2003 (Box 1)
  - Rosenbaum, Paloma, All mixed up: the politics of the "mixed race" student movement., 2004 (Box 1)
  - McReynolds, Anne-Marie, The Harlem YMCA: a photographer's narrative of a community amid transition, recovery, and renaissance., 2000 (Box 1)
  - Kim, Helen, Niseis of the faith: theologizing libertion in the Asian American movement., 2006 (Box 1)
- Theses, Accession 2015-039
  - Shepherd, Miranda Ann, Things that hold us: depression in the black community and a path to better., 2014 May 21